Finding Aid for the Susan Sontag Papers LSC.0612
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 21: Judith Cohen papers, circa 1907-2009
  - Subseries 21.3: Articles and Clippings, 1960s-2009
    - Articles about Sontag, 2000s (Box 358, Folder 2-5)
    - Articles by Judith Cohen, 1977 (Box 359, Folder 1)
    - Articles by David Rieff, 1970s-2007 (Box 359, Folder 2-3)
    - Articles about David Rieff, circa 2008 (Box 359, Folder 4)
    - Articles about Philip Rieff, 1967-2007 (Box 359, Folder 5)
    - Articles about Annie Leibovitz, 1991-2009 (Box 359, Folder 6)
    - Issue of LIFE with image of Judith and nanny, 1962 August 17 (Box 359, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous articles gathered by Judith, 1970s-2000s (Box 359, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 21.4: Sontag Career Materials, 1988-2005
    Materials pertain to lectures, talks, and symposia; prizes and awards; and publicity activities involving Susan Sontag, as well as typescript reproductions of various works.
    SUB-SERIES CONTAINS DIGITAL MATERIALS: Special equipment or further processing may be required for viewing. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
    - Event pamphlets featuring Sontag, circa 2000 (Box 360, Folder 1)
    - Jerusalem prize information, 2001 (Box 360, Folder 2)
    - In America book tour, 2000 (Box 360, Folder 3)
    - PEN Toasts 1988: PEN hosts quote booklet (Box 360, Folder 4)
    - Fredenspreis Award acceptance speech typescript, 2003-2005 (Box 360, Folder 5)
    - Alice in Bed typescript, circa 1993 (Box 360, Folder 6)
    - Drafts for "Pilgrimage" and "Wagner's Fluids", undated (Box 360, Folder 7)
    - "Waiting for Godot in Sarajevo" film, undated (Box 360, Folder 16)
      1 DVD (105 min.)
      Special equipment or further processing may be required for viewing. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
    - Posters for lectures at NYU and Montclair State College, 1988, 2002 (Box 363, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 21.5: Sontag Illness and Memorial, 2004-2006
    Materials related to Susan Sontag's final illness, passing, and memorial.
    - Hospitalization and treatment documentation (Seattle), 2004 (Box 362, Folder 1-3)
    - Consolation cards and letters addressed to Judith, 2004-2005 (Box 362, Folder 4)
    - Judith correspondence regarding Susan's death and memorial, 2004-2006 (Box 362, Folder 5)
    - Obituary draft and final, 2004-2005 (Box 362, Folder 6)
    - Articles and tributes regarding Sontag's death, 2005 (Box 362, Folder 7)
    - Judith travel itinerary to Paris for memorial, 2005 (Box 362, Folder 8)
    - Memorial booklets, 2005 (Box 362, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 21.6: Personal Materials, circa 1956-2007
    Includes materials gathered by or pertaining to Judith Cohen, including travel preparations, notes, and personal ephemera.
    SERIES CONTAINS DIGITAL MATERIALS: Special equipment or further processing may be required for viewing. To access digital materials you must notify the reference desk in advance of your visit.
    - Susan and Judith trip to Europe: research and itineraries, 2002 (Box 360, Folder 8)
    - Judith trip to Italy: research and itinerary, 1987-1988 (Box 360, Folder 9)
    - Judith trip to Los Angeles: itinerary and travel documents, 2000 (Box 360, Folder 10)
    - Judith trip to New York: correspondence and itinerary, 2006 (Box 360, Folder 11)
    - Judith travel diary, circa 1956 (Box 360, Folder 12)
    - Pamphlets and museum guides, 1999-2002 (Box 360, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous materials, 1977-2005 (Box 360, Folder 14)
      Includes handwritten notes and a typed page by Cohen, an issue of "Film Quarterly," a copy of the script for the play "Accomplice" (by Rupert Holmes), and various printouts.
    - Paint sketch portrait of David Rieff, 1956 (Box 363, Folder 2)
    - Letter and compact disc, "Das Konzert November 1989", 1990 (Box 360, Folder 15)
      1 CD.
      Special equipment or further processing may be required for viewing. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page
    - Mildred Sontag's address book, undated (Box 361, Folder 1)
    - Joseph Brodsky Nobel Prize acceptance speech, typescript facsimile, 1987 (Box 361, Folder 2)
    - Library of Congress "Women Who Dare" calendar, featuring Susan Sontag, 2007 (Box 361, Folder 3)
    - Fassbinder Foundation newsletter and book, "Chaos as Usual: Conversations about Rainer Werner Fassbinder", 1997, 2004 (Box 361, Folder 4)
    - "Susan", undated (Box 361, Folder 5)
      1 VHS.
      Audiovisual materials will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
    - "Susan Book TV", undated (Box 361, Folder 6)
    - Land (1975-2002) by Patti Smith (Box 361, Folder 7)
      Liner notes include quotation by Susan Sontag.
      2 CDs.
    - Layout sheets for the book "A Photographer's Life, 1990-2005" by Annie Leibovitz, circa 2005 (Box 364)
    - Books, 1908-2008 (Box 365, Box 366)
      These books come from the library of Judith Cohen and are largely books by Susan Sontag, inscribed to Judith by the author. Also included are books by Annie Leibovitz and David Rieff, as well two readers, which were likely used by Susan in school.
- Accession LSC-0612-2014-03 backlog material, LSC-0612-2014-03 (Box 1, Box 2, Box 3)